<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News</title>
    <description/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 11:38:57 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 11:38:57 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <itunes:author>Emily Kinney</itunes:author>
    <itunes:block>no</itunes:block>
    <atom:link href="https://emilykinneymusic.com/blogs/news.rss" rel="self"/>
    <link>https://emilykinneymusic.com/</link>
    <item>
      <title>Emily in FLAUNT Magazine</title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p><strong>TEN DAYS IN THE VALLEY ACTRESS EMILY KINNEY LOVES HER CASEY, TALKS NEW ALBUM </strong></p>
<p>Emily Kinney knows a radiant character when she comes across one, and since her departure from the hit series, The Walking Dead in 2015 it seems that she has found a few to keep her busy. Her character Nora Everett on Showtimes’ Golden Globe Award-nominated series, Masters of Sex, is a prime example. Kinney has also kept busy exploring her identity through music. And more recently, the actress and songwriter is tackling new projects. </p>
<p>We just had to get a hold of Kinney to chat about these upcoming works, like her mystery show, Ten Days in the Valley (starring Kyra Sedgwick), and the new music she is currently working on. </p>
<p>Kinney is bursting with energy as she begins telling me a little bit about Ten Days in the Valley. “It’s a very fast-moving, mystery, ‘Who did it?’ ‘Who took the girl?’ or ‘Where is she?’ [show],” she says. </p>
<p>I wonder if it was this mystery aspect that attracted her to the script. “I’m really attracted to roles that feel really grounded in reality. Sometimes there’s a fantasy element or like with Walking Dead there’s zombies or things like that. But there’s something about it where the characters feel really grounded in reality and that’s kind of the thing I love so much about Ten Days in the Valley; I felt like I knew who these characters were.”</p>
<p> </p>
<p><img src="//d10j3mvrs1suex.cloudfront.net/u/307167/cb94af8c675e443789337783de0edcce4cd14b08/original/img005.jpg/!!/b:W10=.jpg" class="size_l justify_center border_" /></p>
<p><img src="//d10j3mvrs1suex.cloudfront.net/u/307167/15d445ea35b7180eec8cd5598ffc2208e23aa30e/original/face-feet-b-w.jpg/!!/b:W10=.jpg" class="size_l justify_center border_" /><img src="//d10j3mvrs1suex.cloudfront.net/u/307167/1bf3203dc5821dcc6b401580f5a74b39b08aee13/original/img040.jpg/!!/b:W10=.jpg" class="size_l justify_center border_" /><img src="//d10j3mvrs1suex.cloudfront.net/u/307167/a4ddaa65ca3ff13528ee3c7082ebefe1e73f5336/original/img035.jpg/!!/b:W10=.jpg" class="size_l justify_center border_" /><img src="//d10j3mvrs1suex.cloudfront.net/u/307167/de990f305d1c746da2464b016b111b6f63769c74/original/img007-b-w.jpg/!!/b:W10=.jpg" class="size_l justify_center border_" /><img src="//d10j3mvrs1suex.cloudfront.net/u/307167/e5625fb3e639ef3d770c826c3b1bf5d78d8477d0/original/img008.jpg/!!/b:W10=.jpg" class="size_l justify_center border_" /></p>]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 11:45:22 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://emilykinneymusic.com/news/blog/emily-in-flaunt-magazine</link>
      <guid>https://emilykinneymusic.com/news/blog/emily-in-flaunt-magazine</guid>
      <itunes:author>Emily Kinney</itunes:author>
      <itunes:image href="https://d10j3mvrs1suex.cloudfront.net/u/307167/cb94af8c675e443789337783de0edcce4cd14b08/original/img005.jpg/!!/meta%3AeyJzcmNCdWNrZXQiOiJjb250ZW50LnNpdGV6b29nbGUuY29tIn0%3D.jpg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Billboard Debut's New Music</title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p><img src="//d10j3mvrs1suex.cloudfront.net/u/307167/313d19a3e5dd87e95743c1020de61f1bff80b34b/original/emily-kinney-pc-angelo-sgambati-2017-press-billboard-1548.jpg/!!/b:W10=.jpg" class="size_l justify_center border_" /></p>
<p>Emily Kinney might be best known for her roles on the small screen -- most notably, perhaps, a four-year stint as Beth Greene on The Walking Dead -- but she's been just as busy as an indie pop singer. Kinney has a new track titled "Mermaid Song" (released independently) out this morning (Oct. 26). "Mermaid Song" has Kinney warning a lover that the version of her he sees is an illusion -- "I am a mermaid that you dreamt" -- over a synth and an eerie beat. </p>
<p>"I wrote 'Mermaid Song' after finally leaving behind a relationship where I never felt like I could fully be myself," Kinney tells Billboard. "'Mermaid Song' speaks to a need to be heard and seen and loved authentically. Ben Greenspan produced the song and helped me find cool sounds that made me think of ocean water." </p>
<p>While Kinney could be seen on The Walking Dead, she also could be heard on the soundtrack through "The Parting Glass," which has over 2.7 streams on Spotify. The singer-songwriter's debut full-length album, This Is War, was released in October 2015. </p>
<p>Kinney will be performing on Billboard Facebook Live today at 1:30 p.m. ET; stream it here. </p>
<p>Watch the video, which chronicles a day spent at the pool, and listen to "Mermaid Song" below -- exclusively on Billboard:</p>]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 11:38:57 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://emilykinneymusic.com/news/blog/billboard-debut-s-new-music</link>
      <guid>https://emilykinneymusic.com/news/blog/billboard-debut-s-new-music</guid>
      <itunes:author>Emily Kinney</itunes:author>
      <itunes:image href="https://d10j3mvrs1suex.cloudfront.net/u/307167/0f012a15d822c8740e46bb57a173f3f5f73e317d/original/mokkeoul.jpeg/!!/meta%3AeyJzcmNCdWNrZXQiOiJjb250ZW50LnNpdGV6b29nbGUuY29tIn0%3D.jpg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Marie Claire Feature</title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p><img src="//d10j3mvrs1suex.cloudfront.net/u/307167/fdbf968a519d95be9be9f4df62a3ed5dae867306/original/landscape-1476560199-emily.jpg/!!/b:W10=.jpg" class="size_l justify_center border_" /></p>
<p><span class="font_large"><strong>Actress Emily Kinney Is Making a Lot of Noise—On-Screen and Off </strong></span></p>
<p><span class="font_large"><strong>The 'Walking Dead' and 'Conviction' star has a thing for percussion.</strong></span></p>
<p>By Edith Zimmerman and Photograph By Brian Higbee </p>
<p>Oct 17, 2016 </p>
<p>BRIAN HIGBEE </p>
<p>Practically every TV-watcher knows Emily Kinney (AKA The Walking Dead's Beth Greene and Conviction's Tess Larson). What they *don't* know is that she's kicking ass in her free time, too. Here, a fact sheet about the up-and-coming star. </p>
<p>(P.S. Download her newest single, "Back on Love," on iTunes October 28 and prepare for the feels.) </p>
<p>Age: 31 </p>
<p>Lives in: L.A. and New York City </p>
<p>Hobby: Collecting percussion instruments </p>
<p>Rhythm n' boos: "When I recorded my first EP, I began really paying attention to the texture of songs. I worked with this drummer, Elliot Jacobson, who would bring a huge duffel bag filled with percussive instruments. I started collecting slash stealing people's things. Like my glockenspiel. I first borrowed it from a boy I was dating. It's been four years, so now it's mine." </p>
<p>"I started collecting slash stealing people's things. Like my glockenspiel." </p>
<p>All that racket: "I don't have anything too exotic—I do have an itty-bitty cabasa that I haven't really found a use for, but it's cute. I love cabasas. I have a couple in different sizes that make all different sounds. I also collect little things, like shakers and tambourines, random stuff. Like Popsicle sticks. (If you rub them together, or shake them, they make a sort of clapping noise with a click at the end.) The sticks are from a Mickey Mouse waffle-stick maker." </p>
<p>Play it safe: "Nothing in my collection is so fragile that I wouldn't share with anyone. They are all there to be used, not just displayed. You know, I'm trying to think if anything's broken ever ... not yet!" </p>
<p>Follow her: @emmykinney. </p>
<p>This article appears in the November issue of Marie Claire, on newsstands November 18. Fashion Editor: Sue Choi.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 11:31:28 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://emilykinneymusic.com/news/blog/marie-claire-feature</link>
      <guid>https://emilykinneymusic.com/news/blog/marie-claire-feature</guid>
      <itunes:author>Emily Kinney</itunes:author>
      <itunes:image href="https://d10j3mvrs1suex.cloudfront.net/u/307167/5a0c8c8038c5fa8ef012b787d804b08d44a26040/original/landscape-1476560199-emily.jpg/!!/meta%3AeyJzcmNCdWNrZXQiOiJjb250ZW50LnNpdGV6b29nbGUuY29tIn0%3D.jpg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emily in Darling Magazine</title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p><strong>Wise Thoughts from Darling Friend, Emily Kinney</strong></p>
<p>Darling is a family, and we love to follow women in our community on their various journeys and support their pursuits. In Darling print issue 17, we sat down with actress and musician Emily Kinney for an interview and also had a blast doing a beautiful photo shoot. Now Emily has released a new record, “Oh Jonathan,” so we were excited to chat with her about this project and more. Read on to glean advice from this lovely woman about career, friendships, finances and more. </p>
<p><img src="//d10j3mvrs1suex.cloudfront.net/u/307167/1150717a07127c2d7e3164fefc8988191a7b089c/original/dreamer-asensitivecreativesoul-emilykinney-2-800x1067.jpg/!!/b:W10=.jpg" class="size_l justify_center border_" /></p>
<p>1. You’ve worked in theatre and acted on-screen, but you’ve mentioned music being your first love. What compels you most about music as an artistic genre and what role has music played in your life? </p>
<p>Singing was my first experience with performing and storytelling. Later on, I discovered acting, which I love just as much. Though they take very different approaches when it comes to business, I do feel like they come from similar places in me creatively. </p>
<p>Music can completely change your mood. It can offer such comfort. I connect with a song when I feel the words and melody are describing something I’ve felt before. My parents are music lovers and we went to concerts when I was growing up. It’s a pasttime for me. Going to shows and listening to albums are two of my favorite things to do. And when I’ve moved around to new cities, it’s how I’ve met new friends. I’ve always sought out a musical community. </p>
<p>2. How would you describe the sound and inspiration for “Oh, Jonathan” and how it differs from past projects like “Expired Love” or “This is War?” What did you learn in the process of creating this project? </p>
<p>I tried to leave more open space in this record. I wanted sounds that reminded me of water to be present. I wanted the record to be nice to drive to and I wanted more moments where people had time to absorb the words as I know my songs tend to have a lot of lyrics and information. </p>
<p>I did a lot of exploring in the last three years. I met different producers but eventually met Ben Greenspan and he became my partner. I learned a lot more about the business side of music while making this album. There are still things I’m learning and don’t understand. Through that process, I redefined why I like to make music and who I am making it for. Mostly, I’m making it for myself and the audience that finds the albums; it’s for myself, the fans, and no one else. I’ve learned to have less expectations and to be protective of my artistic instincts and my finances. </p>
<p><img src="//d10j3mvrs1suex.cloudfront.net/u/307167/8440bcb9577a89227500dc83b2fd0e78c33d0313/original/dreamer-asensitivecreativesoul-emilykinney-4-1600x2134.jpg/!!/b:W10=.jpg" class="size_l justify_center border_" /></p>
<p>3. What is one lesson from your upbringing that you’ve carried with you? </p>
<p>I wouldn’t say I’m super religious (I don’t go to church all the time or anything), but praying is important to me. I still say prayers I learned when I was little. </p>
<p>4. Who do you look up to most and why? </p>
<p>My mom and my older sister. They work extremely hard and are always so brave. </p>
<p>5. In your song, “Boy Band Hero” you seem to harness nostalgia and longing of being in your twenties. What do you want people to feel coming away from this record, young women in particular? </p>
<p>I think in “Boy Band Hero” I’m looking back on a relationship that doesn’t really play into my everyday life anymore. I’m saying goodbye and finally realizing I wasn’t always seeing the relationship or the object of my affection clearly. It doesn’t hold the weight it used to in my life. I hope women just feel connected to some of the stories and inspired in some way. </p>
<p><img src="//d10j3mvrs1suex.cloudfront.net/u/307167/1ea0e0777a882ef647b26fc6ebaa99e84ff91519/original/dreamer-asensitivecreativesoul-emilykinney-3-1600x2254.jpg/!!/b:W10=.jpg" class="size_l justify_center border_" /></p>
<p>6. What challenges have you faced as a woman in the industry? </p>
<p>There are many different ways to have a creative career. There is no one right way, so a lot of times you are making it up as you go. Everyone’s path is so different. Especially in music, it’s been harder for me to know who to trust and what exactly people were interested in. </p>
<p>7. How would you advise other young women pursuing an entertainment career? </p>
<p>Be direct and transparent when talking about money. Be direct and transparent whenever possible. It’s okay to change your mind. Ask for advice and really listen and try the advice on before deciding what works for you. No matter how much power or connections someone else might seem to have, you are the boss of your career. Your value as a human being and artist is the same whether you are on a hit television show, not working, or popular or not. It’s more about finishing things you are working on and getting better. </p>
<p>Also, have a few female friends to stay connected to no matter what, no matter how busy. The world is a lot bigger than the entertainment industry. There are a lot of stories to tell. </p>
<p>Images via Darling Issue 17 by Frank Terry.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 11:22:47 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://emilykinneymusic.com/news/blog/emily-in-darling-magazine</link>
      <guid>https://emilykinneymusic.com/news/blog/emily-in-darling-magazine</guid>
      <itunes:author>Emily Kinney</itunes:author>
      <itunes:image href="https://d10j3mvrs1suex.cloudfront.net/u/307167/28f99e572bc2de231ad9b2c1f2fa5799912b0de6/original/dreamer-asensitivecreativesoul-emilykinney-2-800x1067.jpg/!!/meta%3AeyJzcmNCdWNrZXQiOiJjb250ZW50LnNpdGV6b29nbGUuY29tIn0%3D.jpg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vulkan Magazine features Emily Kinney</title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p><img src="//d10j3mvrs1suex.cloudfront.net/u/307167/f0e0c72b9962b12fdb16529eba13a9d2f8c3fea7/original/073.jpg/!!/b:W10=.jpg" class="size_l justify_center border_" />Fans of The Walking Dead know Emily Kinney as the optimist Beth Greene, and they would be unsurprised to know that she’s a singer songwriter, too. VULKAN caught up with Emily to chat about her debut album This Is War, balancing her career goals and down time, and her upcoming series Ten Days In The Valley premiering October 1st, 2017 on ABC. </p>
<p>It must have been quite the move from Nebraska to New York, what was that transition like? <br>It was definitely a different world for me. I didn’t have a lot of money, so making ends meet was the focus of a lot of my time when I first moved to the city. But it was also exciting. I started working at a coffee shop and a lot of those people were artists and became friends. I was excited to be in NYC going after my dreams. Making friends who were also pursuing their dreams or even just a different kind of life than the one they grew up in made a difference in my happiness as well. It was hard to be away from family, but also made me extremely independent. </p>
<p><img src="//d10j3mvrs1suex.cloudfront.net/u/307167/5821497642dd1df1bf35df971b4410e687016efa/original/288.jpg/!!/b:W10=.jpg" class="size_l justify_center border_" /></p>
<p>How was that in comparison to your University experience at Nebraska Wesleyan University? <br>Looking back I really appreciate school and university and the structure and chance to explore it provides. I was so excited to be out of school but now I look back and realize what a gift it is to really study theater and acting and have teachers to guide you. It gives you time to really establish a process for yourself as an artist. You establish standards. Outside of school there are no grades and you make your own rules and although exciting, that can actually be really disorienting after having been a part of a school system since you were 4-5 years old. </p>
<p>Most people know you for your role as Beth in The Walking Dead and as we know, audiences tend to put performers in one box and leave them there. Do you feel that overshadows your music career or do you feel as though one compliments the other? <br>No! Beth actually sang in the show too so I think it’s actually an easy transition for people to make. However, in terms of numbers: The Walking Dead and some of my other tv work has a bigger audience than my music. But because of the show a lot of people are introduced to my music so I guess they compliment each other in terms of exposure. For me as an artist having to creative outlets keeps me very balances and fulfilled. </p>
<p>What similarities personality wise does Casey’s character (Ten Days in The Valley) have to you? What about differences? <br>I think Casey and I are similar in that we fall in love easy. Casey is also a hard worker and really does try her best. Casey though is a bit younger than me and bit more insecure [and] she is much more interested in status than me. I don’t think Casey has a lot of close friends and I don’t think Casey grew up around kind-hearted people in her family. </p>
<p><img src="//d10j3mvrs1suex.cloudfront.net/u/307167/a9c92f8d265bfbc4e9adcd66026171122eb7f861/original/110.jpg/!!/b:W10=.jpg" class="size_l justify_center border_" /></p>
<p>How did you know that music was something that you not only wanted to consume, but create? <br>I’ve always sang since I can remember and learned songs and then performed them. Just always known. I started writing poems in junior high and high school eventually that turned into writing songs and eventually after singing backup for singer-songwriters in NYC, I got up the guts to start recording and doing shows with my own songs. </p>
<p>What is your personal opinion on the difference and challenges between Broadway and being in feature films and a live action series? <br>With theatre you create the through line overnight. It’s physically a different thing because you have to do it 8 times a week so it’s just a different lifestyle than television or film. Also, once you act a scene for tv/film you sort of hand over your performance to directors and editors and you trust them to put the pieces of your performance together. With theatre you have a bit more control over the final product, I feel. </p>
<p>Tell us about your debut album This Is War and how does it compare to Blue Toothbrush and Expired Love? <br>This is a War was just a more full realized completed project than Expired Love and Blue Toothbrush was with my friend Conrad and we were experimenting a lot. I learned a lot about recording and self releasing music through the process of these albums, but I am definitely still learning. My next music is still me and my poems but the instrumentation will be much different. </p>
<p>What is your favourite part about touring? <br>The shows, meeting fans who know the words to your songs!! And the friends you make in your bandmates. Trying the local coffee shops. </p>
<p><img src="//d10j3mvrs1suex.cloudfront.net/u/307167/24eb7de63cb6fb9bc48d3cfe788508f8b333d275/original/312.jpg/!!/b:W10=.jpg" class="size_l justify_center border_" /></p>
<p>What do you like to do on your more relaxed days? <br>SWIM. I love swimming. coffee and going to coffee shops and I love reading and listening to music. For some reason TV and movies have been stressing me out. Even stuff like The Bachelor has been stressing me out. So I barely turn on my tv even though I know there are a million great tv shows right now. But I mean you guys should definitely turn on your tv for 10 Days In The Valley. And I will definitely be watching that!! </p>
<p>What is the most effective Emily Kinney approved life hack/tip that you can share with us? <br>LOVE yourself. Pick up the phone instead of texting. It’s scary at first but you will be happier and it’s nice to hear human voices of the people you communicate with. Do one thing at a time. A good balance of hunger and gratitude daily, keep me happy. You can change your attitude or mood with the right song. </p>
<p>Are you an introvert, extrovert or ambivert and what makes you think you are anyone of those labels? Introvert. I charge up my battery being by myself, but I do love being with friends and going out. I just have to recover and have to have some time to myself after. </p>
<p>Can you share your biggest goal of 2017? <br>I am a chronic list maker and have pages and pages of goals in different areas of my life. So it’s hard to pick one. The biggest overall one is to become a better artist and work on projects I love and can be proud of, music or acting. I want to make the best music I’ve ever made this year!! The more personal ones are to have more fun, be in the moment and it would be nice to fall in love. </p>
<p><img src="//d10j3mvrs1suex.cloudfront.net/u/307167/e66db6208fa9c3a5c851d21fe217c317ed186387/original/208.jpg/!!/b:W10=.jpg" class="size_l justify_center border_" /></p>
<p>Are you at a point where you are pinching yourself because you just can’t believe how far you’ve come? <br>Oh that’s nice! Yes, I’m grateful. Life is good right now. I’m having a lot of fun overall. </p>
<p>Favourite quote of your lifetime? <br>“I have wrestled with the angel and I am stained with light and I have no shame. Neither do I have guilt.” –Mary Oliver</p>
<p> </p>
<p><img src="//d10j3mvrs1suex.cloudfront.net/u/307167/315d9421a28440311b9937254e3db5f8645f0c7b/original/emilycover-arttheme-standard-thumb-big-1000x1254.jpg/!!/b:W10=.jpg" class="size_l justify_center border_" /></p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 11:18:57 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://emilykinneymusic.com/news/blog/vulkan-magazine-features-emily-kinney</link>
      <guid>https://emilykinneymusic.com/news/blog/vulkan-magazine-features-emily-kinney</guid>
      <itunes:author>Emily Kinney</itunes:author>
      <itunes:image href="https://d10j3mvrs1suex.cloudfront.net/u/307167/15375fb9d33018ddf19913d3be997f2525fcb746/original/emilycover-arttheme-standard-thumb-big-1000x1254.jpg/!!/meta%3AeyJzcmNCdWNrZXQiOiJjb250ZW50LnNpdGV6b29nbGUuY29tIn0%3D.jpg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rolling Stone Previews New Music</title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Emily Kinney is ready to make a new album – she even has a concept for it – but she has reached a crossroads with her creativity: she wants to experiment. “I want to work with lots of producers,” she tells Rolling Stone. “I want to write a lot of different kinds of songs and learn before I put out an album. I taught myself guitar but now I’m taking guitar lessons. I want to learn as much as I can.” But that’s not stopping the singer-songwriter and Walking Dead alumna, 31, from putting out new music. </p>
<p>Kinney is releasing a single featuring two new songs she worked on with a friend of hers producing; it’s due out digitally and on vinyl on October 28th. One side, “Back on Love,” is a catchy track about falling in love with an unpredictable guy. Kinney dressed the song in layers of echo, handclaps and piano, a relatively new instrument for her. The other, “Popsicles,” is an acoustic- and piano-adorned song about the difficulty in committing to relationships, in part because she’s always on the move. </p>
<p>She’s currently in Toronto filming a new criminal justice procedural that she likens thematically to Making a Murderer and Serial, titled Conviction, that will premiere on ABC next Monday. It’s her latest locale in a long list. She grew up in Nebraska and, in recent years, has lived in New York and Los Angeles, working on TV shows like Masters of Sex and The Knick. Of course, there were her years in Georgia filming The Walking Dead, on which she played the singing-prone Beth Greene, a character that met her (naturally) unnatural end last year. </p>
<p>Life After 'Dead': Hear 'Walking Dead' Actress Emily Kinney's New Song </p>
<p>Music has been her sole constant – she’s been putting out music since 2011, and self-released her 2015 LP This Is War – that has become a vehicle to talk about her life. “When you’re traveling a lot, you tend to spend a lot of time alone, like in airports,” she says. “So my newer music, specifically ‘Popsicles,’ is about when time for yourself begins and ends and when do you enter into a new relationship after being in so many different ones that don’t work. When is the right time? It’s about feeling lonely and isolated and trying so badly to connect with someone but it’s not ever satisfying. And it makes me almost feverish, angry. So when can I be comfortable in a relationship? … I think all my relationships, even friendships, end up in my songs.” </p>
<p>The meaning behind “Back on Love” is similar to being “back on drugs” – feeling drunk in love with someone who might not be good for you. “Even though it sounds like a fun, happy song, it’s about falling into love again, but it being terrifying and scary but at the same time fun,” she says. “If he calls up, I wanna hang out, like, duh, so much fun, let’s do it. But there’s an uneasiness.” </p>
<p>She recorded the latter tune with her friend Ben Greenspan, who helped her with production techniques and ideas such as handclaps and atmospheric sounds. After clicking in the studio, they also recorded “Popsicles” so she could release music before filming began in Toronto. </p>
<p>As for acting, she’s happy to be working on only one show at the moment. (“It’s enough for right now.”) On the show, she plays Tess Larson – the youngest investigator on a team that works on getting people out of jail who’ve been wrongly accused – and she’s eager to prove herself. She also has a secret past (she has changed her name) and her character develops over the seasons. When Kinney speaks to Rolling Stone, she’s filming the seventh episode and is still learning more about her character. </p>
<p>And even though she’s no longer on the show, The Walking Dead remains a regular part of her life. “In November, it will be, like, two years since I left the show,” she says. “But every day, people come up to me and ask things like, ‘Who did Negan kill?’ I don’t know.” Kinney laughs, recalling the show’s current cliffhanger. “I think that show is just a part of who I am now. But a lot of the fans started listening to my music because of the show, and Beth was a singer, so I’m thankful for it.” </p>
<p>Working with Greenspan helped her explore other songwriting and recording techniques; she’d previously worked with another producer. It also dovetailed into bigger questions she’s been having about her music career. She’s always put out music independently – should she continue to do so? For now, she’s excited about putting out the “Back on Love” seven-inch (“I feel like people are into collecting things again,” she says) and will parse the future of her music career after the first season of Convictionwraps. </p>
<p>“I didn’t want to just wait until two years from now to put out an album,” she says. “When you’re writing a lot, you just want to get your songs out there.”‘</p>]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 11:11:28 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://emilykinneymusic.com/news/blog/rolling-stone-previews-new-music</link>
      <guid>https://emilykinneymusic.com/news/blog/rolling-stone-previews-new-music</guid>
      <itunes:author>Emily Kinney</itunes:author>
      <itunes:image href="https://d10j3mvrs1suex.cloudfront.net/u/307167/f48f7238e8f45fa5cf2e7863ece1ee1add0d0d2b/original/untitled-artwork-33.jpg/!!/meta%3AeyJzcmNCdWNrZXQiOiJjb250ZW50LnNpdGV6b29nbGUuY29tIn0%3D.jpg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Circa Pop Live welcomes Emily Kinney as a Featured Guest</title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Emily sat down with Shira Lazar and Ryan Mitchell at Circa Pop Live where the trio discussed entertainment headlines and chatted about Emily's upcoming record "Oh Jonathan". </p>
<p>To watch Emily's appearance on Circa Pop Live, <a contents="CLICK HERE" data-link-label="" data-link-type="url" href="https://www.circa.com/story/2018/07/05/hollywood/emily-kinney-discusses-what-to-make-of-scarlett-johansson-playing-a-transman-instead-of-hiring-a-transman-for-the-part" target="_blank">CLICK HERE</a>. </p>]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 13:58:55 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://emilykinneymusic.com/news/blog/circa-pop-live-welcomes-emily-kinney-as-a-featured-guest</link>
      <guid>https://emilykinneymusic.com/news/blog/circa-pop-live-welcomes-emily-kinney-as-a-featured-guest</guid>
      <itunes:author>Emily Kinney</itunes:author>
      <itunes:image href="https://d10j3mvrs1suex.cloudfront.net/u/307167/caa1dff7748c33405dc87e1e4bcaf5f2901b8175/original/unknown.jpeg/!!/meta%3AeyJzcmNCdWNrZXQiOiJjb250ZW50LnNpdGV6b29nbGUuY29tIn0%3D.jpg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emily appears on  Johnny Goudie's "How Did I Get Here?" Podcast </title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Recently, Emily sat down with songwriter/podcaster Johnny Goudie for his podcast "How Did I Get Here?". To listen to Emily and Johnny's conversation, please use one of the links below:</p>
<p>Listen on the "How Did I Get Here?" website: <a contents="https://howdidigethere.podbean.com/e/episode-711-nichole-wagner-emily-kinney/&amp;nbsp;" data-link-label="" data-link-type="url" href="https://howdidigethere.podbean.com/e/episode-711-nichole-wagner-emily-kinney/" target="_blank">https://howdidigethere.podbean.com/e/episode-711-nichole-wagner-emily-kinney/ </a></p>
<p>Listen on Spotify: <a contents="https://open.spotify.com/episode/5rze9zFWAoqup6p11TGqpk?si=CH1v01H_TSyu10MfQSqBkg&amp;nbsp;" data-link-label="" data-link-type="url" href="https://open.spotify.com/episode/5rze9zFWAoqup6p11TGqpk?si=CH1v01H_TSyu10MfQSqBkg" target="_self">https://open.spotify.com/episode/5rze9zFWAoqup6p11TGqpk?si=CH1v01H_TSyu10MfQSqBkg </a></p>
<p>Listen on Apple Podcasts: <a contents="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/how-did-i-get-here/id458085551?mt=2" data-link-label="" data-link-type="url" href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/how-did-i-get-here/id458085551?mt=2" target="_blank">https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/how-did-i-get-here/id458085551?mt=2</a></p>]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 13:43:45 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://emilykinneymusic.com/news/blog/emily-appears-on-johnny-goudie-s-how-did-i-get-here-podcast</link>
      <guid>https://emilykinneymusic.com/news/blog/emily-appears-on-johnny-goudie-s-how-did-i-get-here-podcast</guid>
      <itunes:author>Emily Kinney</itunes:author>
      <itunes:image href="https://d10j3mvrs1suex.cloudfront.net/u/307167/4d8dc6c817c63213b938709fd1e096d938ba17d0/original/jg-logo-final-6x6.jpg/!!/meta%3AeyJzcmNCdWNrZXQiOiJjb250ZW50LnNpdGV6b29nbGUuY29tIn0%3D.jpg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Consequence of Sound features "Boy Band Hero" </title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>"Emily Kinney may be perhaps best known as Beth from The Walking Dead, but that character’s been dead for a few seasons now. She’s had plenty of other roles since — including her next one as a young mother whose daughter is battling cancer on Netflix’s forthcoming Messiah — but she’s also been focused on her music career. Today, Kinney has announced her new album, Oh, Jonathan. </p>
<p>Due out August 24th, Oh, Jonathan was largely written and recorded alongside producer Ben Greenspan. Steeped in romantic nostalgia, the record revolved around a crush Kinney had on a pop punk guitarist (one assumed was name Jonathan… get to work, Internet sleuths!) she first saw on MTV"</p>
<p>To read more of Emily's profile on the Consequence of Sound website, <a contents="CLICK HERE." data-link-label="" data-link-type="url" href="https://consequenceofsound.net/2018/06/emily-kinney-oh-jonathan-boy-band-hero/" target="_blank">CLICK HERE.</a> </p>]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 12:23:27 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://emilykinneymusic.com/news/blog/consequence-of-sound-features-boy-band-hero</link>
      <guid>https://emilykinneymusic.com/news/blog/consequence-of-sound-features-boy-band-hero</guid>
      <itunes:author>Emily Kinney</itunes:author>
      <itunes:image href="https://d10j3mvrs1suex.cloudfront.net/u/307167/b0948c81304a662369330288bf1ad94de34715f3/original/logo-for-consequence-of-sound.jpg/!!/meta%3AeyJzcmNCdWNrZXQiOiJjb250ZW50LnNpdGV6b29nbGUuY29tIn0%3D.jpg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emily discusses "Oh Jonathan" with AXS</title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>"Widely known for her stint as Beth Greene on AMC’s “The Walking Dead" (where her music and singing were often featured), Kinney has successfully balanced the role of both musician and actor. And with Oh Jonathan, she's also succeeded in creating an atmospheric and relatable album. Whether it’s that special place in your heart for unrequited love or the feeling of never being exactly sure of what it is you want. Kinney’s music fills that space. Your imagination will fill in the gaps. AXS recently spoke with Kinney about Oh, Jonathan and more in this exclusive new interview"</p>
<p>To read more of Emily's AXS interview, <a contents="CLICK HERE.&amp;nbsp;" data-link-label="" data-link-type="url" href="https://www.axs.com/interview-singer-songwriter-emily-kinney-discusses-her-beautiful-new-a-131648" target="_blank">CLICK HERE</a></p>
<p> </p>]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 12:12:29 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://emilykinneymusic.com/news/blog/axs-features-oh-jonathan-and-extensive-q-a-with-emily</link>
      <guid>https://emilykinneymusic.com/news/blog/axs-features-oh-jonathan-and-extensive-q-a-with-emily</guid>
      <itunes:author>Emily Kinney</itunes:author>
      <itunes:image href="https://d10j3mvrs1suex.cloudfront.net/u/307167/c4c090cf32f360c825c9f4ba410da1f8d0f84eaa/original/wd2zu8v.jpg/!!/meta%3AeyJzcmNCdWNrZXQiOiJjb250ZW50LnNpdGV6b29nbGUuY29tIn0%3D.jpg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"Boy Band Hero" premieres on Baeble.com</title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>"Emily Kinney's video for the song "Boy Band Hero", off of her upcoming album, has a serious nostalgia theme. Whether high school was your peak or your awkward phase, it'll make you reminisce. Directed by Jason Lee Denton, Kinney explained, "I wanted something super simple so that people would really listen to the words" She continued, "I wanted to relate it back to high school when you sit in your classroom, and I can remember my first kiss and going over and over and over it in my head and not paying attention…I wanted to capture that feeling." Other than a single shot of Kinney singing, the video is swirling with images from Kinney's childhood and images of high school. "For me high school was all about marching bands and football games and riding your bike around town." </p>
<p>To read more of Baeble's exclusive premiere, <a contents="CLICK HERE" data-link-label="" data-link-type="url" href="https://www.baeblemusic.com/musicblog/6-27-2018/baeble-first-play-emily-kinney-does-it-all.html" target="_blank">CLICK HERE</a></p>
<p><iframe class="justify_inline" data-video-type="youtube" data-video-id="C-efx6JRxro" data-video-thumb-url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/C-efx6JRxro/mqdefault.jpg" type="text/html" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C-efx6JRxro?rel=0&amp;wmode=transparent&amp;enablejsapi=1" frameborder="0" height="380" width="620" allowfullscreen="true"></iframe></p>]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 11:50:45 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://emilykinneymusic.com/news/blog/boy-band-hero-music-video-out-now</link>
      <guid>https://emilykinneymusic.com/news/blog/boy-band-hero-music-video-out-now</guid>
      <itunes:author>Emily Kinney</itunes:author>
      <itunes:image href="https://d10j3mvrs1suex.cloudfront.net/u/307167/3933c3a48b3d4f1bf5b63ba018b15d65f6487457/original/unnamed.jpg/!!/meta%3AeyJzcmNCdWNrZXQiOiJjb250ZW50LnNpdGV6b29nbGUuY29tIn0%3D.jpg"/>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
